const QuizData = {
  ANGULAR: [
    {
      index: '1',
      question: 'AngularJS is a ____',
      options: [
        'Java framework',
        'JavaScript framework',
        'HTML framework',
        'SQL framework',
      ],
      correct_option: 'JavaScript framework',
    },
    {
      index: '2',
      question: 'AngularJS is perfect for?',
      options: ['MPAs', 'DPAs', 'CPAs', 'SPAs'],
      correct_option: 'SPAs',
    },
    {
      index: '3',
      question:
        'Among the following, on which architectural pattern is AngularJS based?',
      options: [
        'Decorator pattern',
        'Observer pattern',
        'MVVM architecture pattern',
        'MVC architecture pattern',
      ],
      correct_option: 'MVVM architecture pattern',
    },
    {
      index: '4',
      question: 'Angular CLI stands for ____________',
      options: [
        'Angular command-line interceptor',
        'Angular command line',
        'Angular command-line interface',
        'Angular command-line user interfaces',
      ],
      correct_option: 'Angular command-line interface',
    },
    {
      index: '5',
      question: 'Choose the correct syntax for writing AngularJS expression.',
      options: [
        '[expression,]',
        '{{expressions}}',
        '{{{expressions}}}',
        '{expressions}',
      ],
      correct_option: '{{expressions}}',
    },
    {
      index: '6',
      question:
        'Choose the reactor which is used to bind the application data to the HTML view in AngularJS.',
      options: [
        'ng-bind directive',
        'ng-model directive',
        'ng-init directive',
        'ng-app directive',
      ],
      correct_option: 'ng-bind directive',
    },
    {
      index: '7',
      question: 'Choose the correct statement about the lowercase filter.',
      options: [
        'it is a function that takes text as input',
        'the lowercase filter converts a text to lowercase text',
        'both a and b',
        'none of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'the lowercase filter converts a text to lowercase text',
    },
    {
      index: '8',
      question: 'Choose the advantage of Angular JS among the following.',
      options: [
        'it provides reusable components',
        'dependency injection and makes use of separation of concerns',
        'it is unit-testable',
        'all of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'all of the above',
    },
    {
      index: '9',
      question:
        'The functionality of angular controllers in the application is',
      options: [
        'an angular controller is used for displaying the data',
        'an angular controller is used for controlling the data',
        'both a and b',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'an angular controller is used for controlling the data',
    },
    {
      index: '10',
      question: 'The syntax used to create a module in AngularJS is:',
      options: [
        'module(“app”,[,])',
        'var myModule=angular.module();',
        'var myModule = new Module();',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'module(“app”,[,])',
    },
    {
      index: '11',
      question: 'Choose the incorrect AngularJS filter.',
      options: ['orderby', 'email', 'currency', 'lowercas'],
      correct_option: 'email',
    },
    {
      index: '12',
      question: 'Who is the father of AngularJS?',
      options: ['Misko Hevery', 'Brad Green', 'Mike Adams', 'Adam a bronze'],
      correct_option: 'Misko Hevery',
    },
    {
      index: '13',
      question:
        'Choose the directive which is used to find the values of HTML controls to application data.',
      options: ['ng-model', 'ng-init', 'ng-app', 'ng-hide'],
      correct_option: 'ng-model',
    },
    {
      index: '14',
      question: 'Choose the definition of transpilers.',
      options: [
        'Converts source to the library',
        'Convert source to source and then to the library',
        'source to source compiler',
        'all of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'source to source compiler',
    },
    {
      index: '15',
      question: 'Module created by using AngularJS function is known as',
      options: ['module()', 'mod()', 'Angular module()', 'mdl()'],
      correct_option: 'module()',
    },
    {
      index: '16',
      question: 'The total $RootScope an AngularJS application can have is?',
      options: ['0', '1', '2', '3'],
      correct_option: '1',
    },
    {
      index: '17',
      question:
        'Which of the following components is the one which can be injected as a dependency in Angular JS?',
      options: ['Factory', 'Constant', 'Application module', 'Value'],
      correct_option: 'Application module',
    },
    {
      index: '18',
      question: 'Choose the correct definition of deep thinking in AngularJS',
      options: [
        'Deep linking refers to Linking various views to the main page',
        'Deep linking allows you to encode the state of an application in the URL so that it can be bookmarked',
        'Deep linking is an SEO based technique',
        'all of the above',
      ],
      correct_option:
        'Deep linking allows you to encode the state of an application in the URL so that it can be bookmarked',
    },
    {
      index: '19',
      question:
        'Among the following which can be used to write AngularJS directives',
      options: ['Attribute', 'class name', 'Tag', 'all of the above'],
      correct_option: 'all of the above',
    },
    {
      index: '20',
      question: 'AngularJS was developed by which company?',
      options: ['Facebook', 'Google', 'Angular', 'Netflix'],
      correct_option: 'Google',
    },
  ],
  NODEJS: [
    {
      index: '1',
      question: 'Which of the following statements are true?',
      options: [
        'Node.js is a server-side language.',
        'Node.js is a client-side language.',
        'Node.js is both a server and client-side language.',
        'None of the above.',
      ],
      correct_option: 'Node.js is a server-side language.',
    },
    {
      index: '2',
      question: '_____ is an interactive shell that processes Node.',
      options: ['REPL', 'REAL', 'RESP', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'REPL',
    },
    {
      index: '3',
      question: 'What is the full form of REPL?',
      options: [
        'Read Eval Print Loop',
        'Research Eval Program Learn',
        'Read Earn Point Learn',
        'Read Eval Point Loop',
      ],
      correct_option: 'Read Eval Print Loop',
    },
    {
      index: '4',
      question: 'Node.js is written in which language?',
      options: ['C++', 'JavaScript', 'C', 'Java'],
      correct_option: 'JavaScript',
    },
    {
      index: '5',
      question: 'How can we install the node body-parser module?',
      options: [
        'npm install body-parser',
        'node install body-parser',
        'node.js install body-parser',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'npm install body-parser',
    },
    {
      index: '6',
      question: 'Which of the following are examples of node modules?',
      options: ['Express', 'Body-parser', 'Socket.io', 'All of the above'],
      correct_option: 'All of the above',
    },
    {
      index: '7',
      question:
        'To include the HTTP server in the node module, what function do we use?',
      options: ['get()', 'require()', 'createServer()', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'require()',
    },
    {
      index: '8',
      question: 'How can we expose node modules?',
      options: ['exports', 'expose', 'requires', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'exports',
    },
    {
      index: '9',
      question:
        'What method is used to return the current working directory of the process?',
      options: ['cwd()', 'pwd()', 'cmd()', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'cwd()',
    },
    {
      index: '10',
      question: 'Default scope in Node.js application is?',
      options: ['Global', 'Local', 'Local to Object', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'Local',
    },
    {
      index: '11',
      question: 'How many node objects methods are available?',
      options: ['21', '18', '19', '20'],
      correct_option: '18',
    },
    {
      index: '12',
      question: 'We can kill a process in Node.js using the keyboard shortcut?',
      options: ['Ctrl + C', 'Ctrl + B', 'Ctrl + K', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'Ctrl + C',
    },
    {
      index: '13',
      question: 'What is the full form of npm?',
      options: [
        'Node Project Manager',
        'Node Package Manager',
        'New Project Manager',
        'New Package Manager',
      ],
      correct_option: 'Node Package Manager',
    },
    {
      index: '14',
      question: 'How can we initiate a NodeJS file called Hello in Node?',
      options: [
        'Hello,js',
        'node Hello.js',
        'javascript Hello.js',
        'node Hello',
      ],
      correct_option: 'node Hello.js',
    },
    {
      index: '15',
      question: 'NodeJS is supported on which of the following platforms?',
      options: ['Windows', 'MAC OS', 'Unix/Linux', 'All of the above'],
      correct_option: 'All of the above',
    },
    {
      index: '16',
      question: '____ is a debugging tool for NodeJS?',
      options: ['REPL', 'Node Inspector', 'Node Console', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'Node Inspector',
    },
    {
      index: '17',
      question:
        'The node object property which is used to return the node just before the current node is?',
      options: ['localName', 'index', 'previousSibling', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'previousSibling',
    },
    {
      index: '18',
      question: 'The advantages of using node modules are?',
      options: [
        'Provides a means of dividing up tasks',
        'Provides a means of reuse of program code',
        'Provides a means of testing individual parts of the program',
        'All of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'All of the above',
    },
    {
      index: '19',
      question: 'Which of the following are examples of NodeJS streams types?',
      options: ['Writable', 'Duplex', 'Readable', 'All of the above'],
      correct_option: 'All of the above',
    },
    {
      index: '20',
      question: 'The command to install nodemon in NodeJS is?',
      options: [
        'npm install -g nodemon',
        'node install -g nodemon',
        'npm nodemon',
        'node nodemon',
      ],
      correct_option: 'npm install -g nodemon',
    },
  ],
  REACT: [
    {
      index: '1',
      question:
        'Which of the following is used in React.js to increase performance?',
      options: [
        'Virtual DOM',
        'Original DOM',
        'Both A and B',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'Virtual DOM',
    },
    {
      index: '2',
      question: 'What is ReactJS?',
      options: [
        'Server-side framework',
        'user interface framework',
        'both a and b',
        'none of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'user interface framework',
    },
    {
      index: '3',
      question:
        'Identify the one which is used to pass data to components from outside',
      options: ['Render with arguments', 'setState', 'PropTypes', 'props'],
      correct_option: 'props',
    },
    {
      index: '4',
      question: 'Who created React.js?',
      options: ['Jordan Mike', 'Jordan Walke', 'Tim Lee', 'Jordan Lee'],
      correct_option: 'Jordan Walke',
    },
    {
      index: '5',
      question: 'In which language is React.js written?',
      options: ['Python', 'JavaScript', 'Java', 'PHP'],
      correct_option: 'JavaScript',
    },
    {
      index: '6',
      question: 'What is Babel?',
      options: [
        'JavaScript compiler',
        'JavaScript interpreter',
        'JavaScript transpiler',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'JavaScript compiler',
    },
    {
      index: '7',
      question: 'Identify the command used to create a react app.',
      options: [
        'npm install create-react-app',
        'npm install -g create-react-app',
        'install -g create-react-app',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'npm install -g create-react-app',
    },
    {
      index: '8',
      question:
        'Which of the following port is the default where webpack-dev-server runs?',
      options: ['3000', '3306', '3030', '8080'],
      correct_option: '8080',
    },
    {
      index: '9',
      question: 'How many elements can a valid react component return?',
      options: ['1', '2', '3', '4'],
      correct_option: '1',
    },
    {
      index: '10',
      question: 'A state in React.js is also known as?',
      options: [
        'The internal storage of the component',
        'External storage of the component',
        'Permanent storage',
        'All of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'The internal storage of the component',
    },
    {
      index: '11',
      question:
        'Which of the following method is used to access the state of a component from inside of a member function?',
      options: [
        'this.prototype.stateValue',
        'this,getState()',
        'this.values',
        'this.state',
      ],
      correct_option: 'this.values',
    },
    {
      index: '12',
      question: 'What is used to handle code-splitting?',
      options: ['React.lazy', 'React.memo', 'React.fallback', 'React.split'],
      correct_option: 'React.lazy',
    },
    {
      index: '13',
      question:
        'What are arbitrary inputs of components in react also known as?',
      options: ['Elements', 'Props', 'Keys', 'Ref'],
      correct_option: 'Props',
    },
    {
      index: '14',
      question: 'In MVC, what does React.js act as?',
      options: ['Model', 'Controller', 'Router', 'Middleware'],
      correct_option: 'Controller',
    },
    {
      index: '15',
      question:
        'Which of the following is used to access a function fetch()  from h1 element in JSX?',
      options: [
        '<h1>${fetch()}</h1>',
        '<h1>{fetch}</h1>',
        '<h1>${fetch}</h1>',
        '<h1>{fetch()}</h1>',
      ],
      correct_option: '<h1>{fetch()}</h1>',
    },
    {
      index: '16',
      question:
        'Among The following options, choose the one which helps react for keeping their data uni-directional?',
      options: ['DOM', 'Flux', 'JSX', 'Props'],
      correct_option: 'Flux',
    },
    {
      index: '17',
      question:
        'Using which of the following command can prevent default behaviour at in react?',
      options: [
        'preventDefault()',
        'avoidDefault()',
        'revokeDefault()',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'preventDefault()',
    },
    {
      index: '18',
      question: 'Identify the smallest building block of React.JS.',
      options: ['Props', 'Elements', 'Components', 'None of the above'],
      correct_option: 'Components',
    },
    {
      index: '19',
      question: 'What is ReactJS mainly used for building?',
      options: [
        'Database',
        'Connectivity',
        'User interface',
        'Design platform',
      ],
      correct_option: 'User interface',
    },
    {
      index: '20',
      question:
        'Which of the following function is used to change the state of react component?',
      options: [
        'this.setState()',
        'this.state()',
        'this.setChangeState()',
        'None of the above',
      ],
      correct_option: 'this.setState()',
    },
  ],
};

export default QuizData;
